cutediyprojects.com 2019-03-05

# Privacy policy – Cute DIY Projects

**Privacy policy**

**1\. Introduction**

1.1 We are committed to safeguarding the privacy of [our website visitors and service users].

1.2 This policy applies where we are acting as a data controller with respect to the personal data of [our website visitors and service users]; in other words, where we determine the purposes and means of the processing of that personal data.

1.3 We use cookies on our website. Insofar as those cookies are not strictly necessary for the provision of [our website and services], we will ask you to consent to our use of cookies when you first visit our website.

1.4 Our website incorporates privacy controls which affect how we will process your personal data. By using the privacy controls, you can [specify whether you would like to receive direct marketing communications and limit the publication of your information]. You can access the privacy controls via _[URL]_.

1.5 In this policy, “we”, “us” and “our” refer to _[data controller name]_.[ For more information about us, see Section 12.]

**2\. How we use your personal data**

2.1 In this Section 2 we have set out:

(a) the general categories of personal data that we may process;

(b) [in the case of personal data that we did not obtain directly from you, the source and specific categories of that data];

(c) the purposes for which we may process personal data; and

(d) the legal bases of the processing.

2.2 We may process [data about your use of our website and services] (“ **usage data** “). The usage data may include [your IP address, geographical location, browser type and version, operating system, referral source, length of visit, page views and website navigation paths, as well as information about the timing, frequency and pattern of your service use]. The source of the usage data is [our analytics tracking system]. This usage data may be processed [for the purposes of analysing the use of the website and services]. The legal basis for this processing is [consent] OR [our legitimate interests, namely [monitoring and improving our website and services]] OR [ _[specify basis]_ ].

2.3 We may process [your account data] (“ **account data** “).[ The account data may [include your name and email address].][ The source of the account data is [you or your employer].] The account data may be processed [for the purposes of operating our website, providing our services, ensuring the security of our website and services, maintaining back-ups of our databases and communicating with you.] The legal basis for this processing is [consent] OR [our legitimate interests, namely [the proper administration of our website and business]] OR [the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into such a contract] OR [ _[specify basis]_ ].

2.4 We may process [your information included in your personal profile on our website] (“ **profile data** “).[ The profile data may include [your name, address, telephone number, email address, profile pictures, gender, date of birth, relationship status, interests and hobbies, educational details and employment details].] The profile data may be processed for [the purposes of enabling and monitoring your use of our website and services]. The legal basis for this processing is [consent] OR [our legitimate interests, namely [the proper administration of our website and business]] OR [the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at you request, to enter into such a contract] OR [ _[specify basis]_ ].

2.5 We may process [your personal data that are provided in the course of the use of our services] (“ **service data** “).[ The service data may include _[specify data]_.][ The source of the service data is [you or your employer].] The service data may be processed [for the purposes of operating our website, providing our services, ensuring the security of our website and services, maintaining back-ups of our databases and communicating with you]. The legal basis for this processing is [consent] OR [our legitimate interests, namely [the proper administration of our website and business]] OR [the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into such a contract] OR [ _[specify basis]_ ].

2.6 We may process [information that you post for publication on our website or through our services] (“ **publication data** “). The publication data may be processed [for the purposes of enabling such publication and administering our website and services]. The legal basis for this processing is [consent] OR [our legitimate interests, namely [the proper administration of our website and business]] OR [the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into such a contract] OR [ _[specify basis]_ ].

2.7 We may process [information contained in any enquiry you submit to us regarding goods and/or services] (“ **enquiry data** “). The enquiry data may be processed [for the purposes of offering, marketing and selling relevant goods and/or services to you]. The legal basis for this processing is [consent] OR [ _[specify basis]_ ].

2.8 We may process [information relating to our customer relationships, including customer contact information] (“ **customer relationship data** “).[ The customer relationship data may include [your name, your employer, your job title or role, your contact details, and information contained in communications between us and you or your employer].][ The source of the customer relationship data is [you or your employer].] The customer relationship data may be processed [for the purposes of managing our relationships with customers, communicating with customers, keeping records of those communications and promoting our products and services to customers]. The legal basis for this processing is [consent] OR [our legitimate interests, namely [the proper management of our customer relationships]] OR [ _[specify basis]_ ].

2.9 We may process [information relating to transactions, including purchases of goods and services, that you enter into with us and/or through our website] (“ **transaction data** “).[ The transaction data may include [your contact details, your card details and the transaction details].] The transaction data may be processed [for the purpose of supplying the purchased goods and services and keeping proper records of those transactions]. The legal basis for this processing is [the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into such a contract and our legitimate interests, namely [the proper administration of our website and business]] OR [ _[specify basis]_ ].

2.10 We may process [information that you provide to us for the purpose of subscribing to our email notifications and/or newsletters] (“ **notification data** “). The notification data may be processed [for the purposes of sending you the relevant notifications and/or newsletters]. The legal basis for this processing is [consent] OR [the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into such a contract] OR [ _[specify basis]_ ].

2.11 We may process [information contained in or relating to any communication that you send to us] (“ **correspondence data** “). The correspondence data may include [the communication content and metadata associated with the communication].[ Our website will generate the metadata associated with communications made using the website contact forms.] The correspondence data may be processed [for the purposes of communicating with you and record-keeping]. The legal basis for this processing is [our legitimate interests, namely [the proper administration of our website and business and communications with users]] OR [ _[specify basis]_ ].

2.12 We may process _[identify general category of data]_.[ This data may include _[list specific items of data]_.][ The source of this data is _[identify source]_.] This data may be processed for _[specify purposes]_. The legal basis for this processing is [consent] OR [our legitimate interests, namely _[specify legitimate interests]_ ] OR [the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into such a contract] OR [ _[specify basis]_ ].

2.13 We may process [any of your personal data identified in this policy] where necessary for [the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure]. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely [the protection and assertion of our legal rights, your legal rights and the legal rights of others].

2.14 We may process [any of your personal data identified in this policy] where necessary for [the purposes of obtaining or maintaining insurance coverage, managing risks, or obtaining professional advice]. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely [the proper protection of our business against risks].

2.15 In addition to the specific purposes for which we may process your personal data set out in this Section 2, we may also process [any of your personal data] where such processing is necessary[ for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or] in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.

2.16 Please do not supply any other person’s personal data to us, unless we prompt you to do so.

**3\. Providing your personal data to others**

3.1 We may disclose [your personal data] to any member of our group of companies (this means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and all its subsidiaries) insofar as reasonably necessary for the purposes, and on the legal bases, set out in this policy.[ Information about our group of companies can be found at _[URL]_.]

3.2 We may disclose [your personal data] to [our insurers and/or professional advisers] insofar as reasonably necessary for the purposes of [obtaining or maintaining insurance coverage, managing risks, obtaining professional advice, or the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure].

3.3 We may disclose _[specify personal data category or categories]_ to [our suppliers or subcontractors][ identified at _[URL]_ ] insofar as reasonably necessary for _[specify purposes]_.

3.4 Financial transactions relating to [our website and services] [are] OR [may be] handled by our payment services providers, _[identify PSPs]_. We will share transaction data with our payment services providers only to the extent necessary for the purposes of [processing your payments, refunding such payments and dealing with complaints and queries relating to such payments and refunds]. You can find information about the payment services providers’ privacy policies and practices at _[URLs]_.

3.5 We may disclose [your enquiry data] to [one or more of those selected third party suppliers of goods and services identified on our website] for the purpose of [enabling them to contact you so that they can offer, market and sell to you relevant goods and/or services].[ Each such third party will act as a data controller in relation to the enquiry data that we supply to it; and upon contacting you, each such third party will supply to you a copy of its own privacy policy, which will govern that third party’s use of your personal data.]

3.6 In addition to the specific disclosures of personal data set out in this Section 3, we may disclose your personal data where such disclosure is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.[ We may also disclose your personal data where such disclosure is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure.]

**4\. International transfers of your personal data**

4.1 In this Section 4, we provide information about the circumstances in which your personal data may be transferred to [countries outside the European Economic Area (EEA)].

4.2 We[ and our other group companies] have [offices and facilities] in _[specify countries]_.[ The European Commission has made an “adequacy decision” with respect to [the data protection laws of each of these countries].][ Transfers to [each of these countries] will be protected by appropriate safeguards, namely [the use of standard data protection clauses adopted or approved by the European Commission, a copy of which can be obtained from _[source]_ ] OR [the use of binding corporate rules, a copy of which you can obtain from _[source]_ ] OR [ _[specify appropriate safeguards and means to obtain a copy]_ ].]

4.3 The hosting facilities for our website are situated in _[specify countries]_.[ The European Commission has made an “adequacy decision” with respect to [the data protection laws of each of these countries].][ Transfers to [each of these countries] will be protected by appropriate safeguards, namely [the use of standard data protection clauses adopted or approved by the European Commission, a copy of which you can obtain from _[source]_ ] OR [ _[specify appropriate safeguards and means to obtain a copy]_ ].]

4.4 _[Specify category or categories of supplier or subcontractor]_ [is] OR [are] situated in _[specify countries]_.[ The European Commission has made an “adequacy decision” with respect to [the data protection laws of each of these countries].][ Transfers to [each of these countries] will be protected by appropriate safeguards, namely [the use of standard data protection clauses adopted or approved by the European Commission, a copy of which can be obtained from _[source]_ ] OR [ _[specify appropriate safeguards and means to obtain a copy]_ ].]

4.5 You acknowledge that [personal data that you submit for publication through our website or services] may be available, via the internet, around the world. We cannot prevent the use (or misuse) of such personal data by others.

**5\. Retaining and deleting personal data**

5.1 This Section 5 sets out our data retention policies and procedure, which are designed to help ensure that we comply with our legal obligations in relation to the retention and deletion of personal data.

5.2 Personal data that we process for any purpose or purposes shall not be kept for longer than is necessary for that purpose or those purposes.

5.3 We will retain your personal data as follows:

(a) _[personal data category or categories]_ will be retained for a minimum period of _[period]_ following _[date]_ , and for a maximum period of _[period]_ following _[date]_.

_[additional list items]_

5.4 In some cases it is not possible for us to specify in advance the periods for which your personal data will be retained. In such cases, we will determine the period of retention based on the following criteria:

(a) the period of retention of _[personal data category]_ will be determined based on _[specify criteria]_.

_[additional list items]_

5.5 Notwithstanding the other provisions of this Section 5, we may retain your personal data where such retention is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.

**6\. Amendments**

6.1 We may update this policy from time to time by publishing a new version on our website.

6.2 You should check this page occasionally to ensure you are happy with any changes to this policy.

6.3 We [may] OR [will] notify you of [changes] OR [significant changes] to this policy [by email or through the private messaging system on our website].

**7\. Your rights**

7.1 In this Section 7, we have summarised the rights that you have under data protection law. Some of the rights are complex, and not all of the details have been included in our summaries. Accordingly, you should read the relevant laws and guidance from the regulatory authorities for a full explanation of these rights.

7.2 Your principal rights under data protection law are:

(a) the right to access;

(b) the right to rectification;

(c) the right to erasure;

(d) the right to restrict processing;

(e) the right to object to processing;

(f) the right to data portability;

(g) the right to complain to a supervisory authority; and

(h) the right to withdraw consent.

7.3 You have the right to confirmation as to whether or not we process your personal data and, where we do, access to the personal data, together with certain additional information. That additional information includes details of the purposes of the processing, the categories of personal data concerned and the recipients of the personal data. Providing the rights and freedoms of others are not affected, we will supply to you a copy of your personal data. The first copy will be provided free of charge, but additional copies may be subject to a reasonable fee.[ You can access [your personal data] by visiting _[URL]_ when logged into our website.]

7.4 You have the right to have any inaccurate personal data about you rectified and, taking into account the purposes of the processing, to have any incomplete personal data about you completed.

7.5 In some circumstances you have the right to the erasure of your personal data without undue delay. Those circumstances include: [the personal data are no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which they were collected or otherwise processed; you withdraw consent to consent-based processing; you object to the processing under certain rules of applicable data protection law; the processing is for direct marketing purposes; and the personal data have been unlawfully processed]. However, there are exclusions of the right to erasure. The general exclusions include where processing is necessary: [for exercising the right of freedom of expression and information; for compliance with a legal obligation; or for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims].

7.6 In some circumstances you have the right to restrict the processing of your personal data. Those circumstances are: you contest the accuracy of the personal data; processing is unlawful but you oppose erasure; we no longer need the personal data for the purposes of our processing, but you require personal data for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; and you have objected to processing, pending the verification of that objection. Where processing has been restricted on this basis, we may continue to store your personal data. However, we will only otherwise process it: with your consent; for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; for the protection of the rights of another natural or legal person; or for reasons of important public interest.

7.7 You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data on grounds relating to your particular situation, but only to the extent that the legal basis for the processing is that the processing is necessary for: the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of any official authority vested in us; or the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by us or by a third party. If you make such an objection, we will cease to process the personal information unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override your interests, rights and freedoms, or the processing is for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

7.8 You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data for direct marketing purposes (including profiling for direct marketing purposes). If you make such an objection, we will cease to process your personal data for this purpose.

7.9 You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data for scientific or historical research purposes or statistical purposes on grounds relating to your particular situation, unless the processing is necessary for the performance of a task carried out for reasons of public interest.

7.10 To the extent that the legal basis for our processing of your personal data is:

(a) consent; or

(b) that the processing is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are party or in order to take steps at your request prior to entering into a contract,

and such processing is carried out by automated means, you have the right to receive your personal data from us in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format. However, this right does not apply where it would adversely affect the rights and freedoms of others.

7.11 If you consider that our processing of your personal information infringes data protection laws, you have a legal right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority responsible for data protection. You may do so in the EU member state of your habitual residence, your place of work or the place of the alleged infringement.

7.12 To the extent that the legal basis for our processing of your personal information is consent, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time. Withdrawal will not affect the lawfulness of processing before the withdrawal.

7.13 You may exercise any of your rights in relation to your personal data [by written notice to us] OR [by _[methods]_ ][, in addition to the other methods specified in this Section 7].

**8\. About cookies**

8.1 A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server.

8.2 Cookies may be either “persistent” cookies or “session” cookies: a persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless deleted by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed.

8.3 Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.

**9\. Cookies that we use**

9.1 We use cookies for the following purposes:

(a) [authentication – we use cookies [to identify you when you visit our website and as you navigate our website][ (cookies used for this purpose are: _[identify cookies]_ )]];

(b) [status – we use cookies [to help us to determine if you are logged into our website][ (cookies used for this purpose are: _[identify cookies]_ )]];

(c) [personalisation – we use cookies [to store information about your preferences and to personalise the website for you][ (cookies used for this purpose are: _[identify cookies]_ )]];

(d) [security – we use cookies [as an element of the security measures used to protect user accounts, including preventing fraudulent use of login credentials, and to protect our website and services generally][ (cookies used for this purpose are: _[identify cookies]_ )]];

(e) [advertising – we use cookies [to help us to display advertisements that will be relevant to you][ (cookies used for this purpose are: _[identify cookies]_ )]];

(f) [analysis – we use cookies [to help us to analyse the use and performance of our website and services][ (cookies used for this purpose are: _[identify cookies]_ )]]; and

(g) [cookie consent – we use cookies [to store your preferences in relation to the use of cookies more generally][ (cookies used for this purpose are: _[identify cookies]_ )]].

_[additional list items]_

**10\. Cookies used by our service providers**

10.1 Our service providers use cookies and those cookies may be stored on your computer when you visit our website.

10.2 We use Google Analytics to analyse the use of our website. Google Analytics gathers information about website use by means of cookies. The information gathered relating to our website is used to create reports about the use of our website. Google’s privacy policy is available at: <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>.[ The relevant cookies are: _[identify cookies]_.]

10.3 [We publish Google AdSense interest-based advertisements on our website. These are tailored by Google to reflect your interests. To determine your interests, Google will track your behaviour on our website and on other websites across the web using cookies.] OR [We publish Google AdSense advertisements on our website. To determine your interests, Google will track your behaviour on our website and on other websites across the web using cookies. This behaviour tracking allows Google to tailor the advertisements that you see on other websites to reflect your interests (but we do not publish interest-based advertisements on our website).] You can view, delete or add interest categories associated with your browser by visiting: [https://adssettings.google.com](https://adssettings.google.com/). You can also opt out of the AdSense partner network cookie using those settings or using the Network Advertising Initiative’s multi-cookie opt-out mechanism at: [http://optout.networkadvertising.org](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/). However, these opt-out mechanisms themselves use cookies, and if you clear the cookies from your browser your opt-out will not be maintained. To ensure that an opt-out is maintained in respect of a particular browser, you may wish to consider using the Google browser plug-ins available at: <https://support.google.com/ads/answer/7395996>.[ The relevant cookies are: _[identify cookies]_.]

10.4 We use _[identify service provider]_ to _[specify service]_. This service uses cookies for _[specify purpose(s)]_. You can view the privacy policy of this service provider at _[URL]_.[ The relevant cookies are: _[identify cookies]_.]

**11\. Managing cookies**

11.1 Most browsers allow you to refuse to accept cookies and to delete cookies. The methods for doing so vary from browser to browser, and from version to version. You can however obtain up-to-date information about blocking and deleting cookies via these links:

(a) <https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en> (Chrome);

(b) <https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences> (Firefox);

(c) <http://www.opera.com/help/tutorials/security/cookies/> (Opera);

(d) <https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies> (Internet Explorer);

(e) <https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411> (Safari); and

(f) <https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-10-microsoft-edge-and-privacy> (Edge).

_[additional list items]_

11.2 Blocking all cookies will have a negative impact upon the usability of many websites.

11.3 If you block cookies, you will not be able to use all the features on our website.

**12\. Our details**

12.1 This website is owned and operated by _[name]_.

12.2 We are registered in [England and Wales] under registration number _[number]_ , and our registered office is at _[address]_.

12.3 Our principal place of business is at _[address]_.

12.4 You can contact us:

(a) [by post, to [the postal address given above]];

(b) [using our website contact form];

(c) [by telephone, on [the contact number published on our website from time to time]]; or

(d) [by email, using [the email address published on our website from time to time]].

**Privacy policy: drafting notes**

This privacy policy is a shorter and simpler version of our privacy and cookies policy document, and may be used in relation to a wide variety of different kinds of website.

The primary purpose of a privacy policy is to assist a website operator to comply with information disclosure obligations under data protection legislation. From 25 May 2018 in the UK and elsewhere in the EU, that includes the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). Failure to comply may lead to civil liability and/or criminal law penalties.

This policy has been updated to take full account of the GDPR.

You should consider whether you need to take specialist legal advice on data protection. If you collect sensitive personal information (such as information about a person’s health, sexuality or political affiliations), or if you collect personal information from children or about children, you should always take advice before using this – or indeed any other – privacy policy template. In any case, use of a privacy policy is only one aspect of data protection compliance.

This document also includes optional provisions dealing with cookie-related disclosures.

**Section 1: Introduction**

**Section 1.2**

“Personal data” is defined in Article 4(1) of the GDPR:

“(1) ‘personal data’ means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person (‘data subject’); an identifiable natural person is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identifier such as a name, an identification number, location data, an online identifier or to one or more factors specific to the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity of that natural person”.

The inclusion of this statement in your privacy policy will not in itself satisfy the requirements of the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003 as regards consent to the use of cookies. Guidance concerning methods of obtaining such consent is included on the Information Commissioner’s website (http://www.ico.gov.uk).

**Section 2: How we use your personal data**

Article 13(1) of the GDPR provides that:

“(1) Where personal data relating to a data subject are collected from the data subject, the controller shall, at the time when personal data are obtained, provide the data subject with all of the following information: … (c) the purposes of the processing for which the personal data are intended as well as the legal basis for the processing; (d) where the processing is based on point (f) of Article 6(1), the legitimate interests pursued by the controller or by a third party”.

Article 6(1)(f) of the GDPR provides that:

“(1) Processing shall be lawful only if and to the extent that at least one of the following applies: … (f) processing is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by the controller or by a third party, except where such interests are overridden by the interests or fundamental rights and freedoms of the data subject which require protection of personal data, in particular where the data subject is a child.”

**Section 2.1**

Article 14 of the GDPR, which applies where personal information is not obtained from the data subject, provides that information about “the categories of personal data concerned” must be supplied to data subjects.

Article 13 of the GDPR, which applies where personal information is obtained from the data subject, does not include an equivalent provision.

Nonetheless, we have included references to general categories of data in this document, because this facilitates the identification of particular purposes of processing and the legal bases of processing – information which does need to be provided under Article 13.

**Section 3: Providing your personal data to others**

Article 13(1)(e) of the GDPR requires that where personal data are collected from the data subject, the data controller must provide the data subject with information about “the recipients or categories of recipients of the personal data”.

Equivalent rules for data collected from someone other than the data subject are in Article 14(1)(e).

**Section 3.1**

**Commercial affiliation**

This type of service allows this Website to display advertisements for third-party products or services. Ads can be displayed either as advertising links or as banners using various kinds of graphics.Clicks on the icon or banner posted on the Application are tracked by the third-party services listed below, and are shared with this Website.For details of which data are collected, please refer to the privacy policy of each service.

Amazon Affiliation (Amazon)

Amazon Affiliation is a commercial affiliation service provided by Amazon.com Inc.

Personal Data collected:Cookies and Usage Data.

Place of processing:United States–[Privacy Policy](https://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html?nodeId=201909010).

**Section 4: International transfers of your personal data**

Article 13(1)(f) of the GDPR requires that data controllers disclose to data subjects “where applicable, the fact that the controller intends to transfer personal data to a third country or international organisation and the existence or absence of an adequacy decision by the Commission, or in the case of transfers referred to in Article 46 [transfers subject to appropriate safeguards] or 47 [binding corporate rules], or the second subparagraph of Article 49(1) [limited transfers for compelling legitimate interests], reference to the appropriate or suitable safeguards and the means by which to obtain a copy of them or where they have been made available”.

**Section 5: Retaining and deleting personal data**

Article 5(1)(e) of the GDPR sets out the storage limitation, one of the fundamental rules of the regime:

“Personal data shall be: … kept in a form which permits identification of data subjects for no longer than is necessary for the purposes for which the personal data are processed; personal data may be stored for longer periods insofar as the personal data will be processed solely for archiving purposes in the public interest, scientific or historical research purposes or statistical purposes in accordance with Article 89(1) subject to implementation of the appropriate technical and organisational measures required by this Regulation in order to safeguard the rights and freedoms of the data subject … “.

**Section 7: Your rights**

Article 13(2) of the GDPR provides that, where personal data is collected from a data subject, certain information about data subject rights must be provided:

“In addition to the information referred to in paragraph 1, the controller shall, at the time when personal data are obtained, provide the data subject with the following further information necessary to ensure fair and transparent processing: … (b) the existence of the right to request from the controller access to and rectification or erasure of personal data or restriction of processing concerning the data subject or to object to processing as well as the right to data portability; (c) where the processing is based on point (a) of Article 6(1) or point (a) of Article 9(2), the existence of the right to withdraw consent at any time, without affecting the lawfulness of processing based on consent before its withdrawal; …”.

Similar provisions are set out in Article 14 in relation to personal data which is not collected from the relevant data subject.

**Section 7.3**

The right to access is set out in Article 15 of the GDPR.

**Section 7.4**

The right to rectification is set out in Article 16 of the GDPR.

**Section 7.5**

The right to erasure (or right to be forgotten) is set out in Article 17 of the GDPR, and must be notified to data subjects under Articles 13(2)(b), 14(2)(c) and 15(1)(e) of the GDPR.

Consider modifying the highlighted circumstances and exclusions, depending upon what will be most relevant to your processing.

**Section 7.6**

Article 18(1) of the GDPR states:

“The data subject shall have the right to obtain from the controller restriction of processing where one of the following applies: (a) the accuracy of the personal data is contested by the data subject, for a period enabling the controller to verify the accuracy of the personal data; (b) the processing is unlawful and the data subject opposes the erasure of the personal data and requests the restriction of their use instead; (c) the controller no longer needs the personal data for the purposes of the processing, but they are required by the data subject for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; (d) the data subject has objected to processing pursuant to Article 21(1) pending the verification whether the legitimate grounds of the controller override those of the data subject.

**Section 7.7**

The right to object to processing is detailed in Article 21 of the GDPR, and must be notified to data subjects under Articles 21(4), 13(2)(b) and 14(2)(c).

**Section 7.8**

Article 21(3) of the GDPR states:

“Where the data subject objects to processing for direct marketing purposes, the personal data shall no longer be processed for such purposes.”

This right is set out in Article 21(6) of the GDPR.

**Section 7.10**

The right to data portability is set out in full in Article 20 of the GDPR, and must be notified to data subjects under Articles 13(2)(b) and 14(2)(c).

**Section 7.11**

The right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority is set out in Article 77 of the GDPR, and must be notified to data subjects under Articles 13(2)(d), 14(2)(e) and 15(1)(f).

**Section 7.12**

Article 7(3) of the GDPR sets out the right of withdrawal. The right must be notified to data subjects under Articles 13(2)(c) and 14(2)(d). See also Article 17(1)(b).

**Section 8: About cookies**

**Section 10: Cookies used by our service providers**

If the website sets any other cookies to users’ machines that track behaviour, information about those cookies will also need to be disclosed.

**Section 11: Managing cookies**

**Section 12: Our details**

UK companies must provide their corporate names, their registration numbers, their place of registration and their registered office address on their websites (although not necessarily in this document).

Sole traders and partnerships that carry on a business in the UK under a “business name” (i.e. a name which is not the name of the trader/names of the partners or certain other specified classes of name) must also make certain website disclosures: (i) in the case of a sole trader, the individual’s name; (ii) in the case of a partnership, the name of each member of the partnership; and (iii) in either case, in relation to each person named, an address in the UK at which service of any document relating in any way to the business will be effective. All websites covered by the Electronic Commerce (EC Directive) Regulations 2002 must provide a geographic address (not a PO Box number) and an email address. All website operators covered by the Provision of Services Regulations 2009 must also provide a telephone number.

### Displaying content from external platforms

This type of service allows you to view content hosted on external platforms directly from the pages of this Website and interact with them.This type of service might still collect web traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when Users do not use it.

#### Google Fonts (Google Inc.)

Google Fonts is a typeface visualization service provided by Google Inc. that allows this Website to incorporate content of this kind on its pages.

Personal Data collected:Usage Data and various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.

Place of processing:United States–[Privacy Policy](https://www.google.it/intl/policies/privacy/).Privacy Shield participant.

#### YouTube video widget (Google Inc.)

YouTube is a video content visualization service provided by Google Inc. that allows this Website to incorporate content of this kind on its pages.

Personal Data collected:Cookies and Usage Data.

Place of processing:United States–[Privacy Policy](https://www.google.it/intl/en/policies/privacy/).Privacy Shield participant.

#### YouTube video widget without cookies (Google Inc.)

YouTube is a video content visualization service provided by Google Inc. that allows this Website to incorporate content of this kind on its pages.This widget is set up in a way that ensures that YouTube won’t store information and cookies about Users on this Website unless they play the video.

Personal Data collected:Usage Data.

Place of processing:United States–[Privacy Policy](https://www.google.it/intl/en/policies/privacy/).Privacy Shield participant.

### Interaction with external social networks and platforms

This type of service allows interaction with social networks or other external platforms directly from the pages of this Website.The interaction and information obtained through this Website are always subject to the User’s privacy settings for each social network.This type of service might still collect traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when Users do not use it.

#### Facebook Like button and social widgets (Facebook, Inc.)

The Facebook Like button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Facebook social network provided by Facebook, Inc.

Personal Data collected:Cookies and Usage Data.

Place of processing:United States–[Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation).Privacy Shield participant.

#### Pinterest “Pin it” button and social widgets (Pinterest)

The Pinterest “Pin it” button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Pinterest platform provided by Pinterest Inc.

Personal Data collected:Cookies and Usage Data.

Place of processing:United States–[Privacy Policy](https://about.pinterest.com/en/privacy-policy).

## Facebook permissions asked by this Website

This Website may ask for some Facebook permissions allowing it to perform actions with the User’s Facebook account and to retrieve information, including Personal Data, from it. This service allows this Website to connect with the User’s account on the Facebook social network, provided by Facebook Inc.

For more information about the following permissions, refer to the [Facebook permissions documentation](https://developers.facebook.com/docs/authentication/permissions/) and to the [Facebook privacy policy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/).

## Website and data controller contact

cutediyprojects.com

**Owner contact email:**   **hello@cutediyprojects.com**

**Section 13.1**

If you require any more information or have any questions about our privacy policy, please feel free to contact us by email at hello@warmcozyhome.com

At warmcozyhome.com, the privacy of our visitors is of extreme importance to us. This privacy policy document outlines the types of personal information is received and collected by warmcozyhome.com and how it is used.

**Log Files** Like many other Web sites, warmcozyhome.com makes use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol ( IP ) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider ( ISP ), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses, and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable.

**Cookies and Web Beacons** warmcozyhome.com does use cookies to store information about visitors preferences, record user-specific information on which pages the user access or visit, customize Web page content based on visitors browser type or other information that the visitor sends via their browser.DoubleClick DART Cookie.:: Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on warmcozyhome.com..:: Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to users based on their visit to warmcozyhome.com and other sites on the Internet..:: Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL – http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.htmlSome of our advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our site. Our advertising partners include:

**Google Adsense** **Clickbank** **Amazon**

We are a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for us to earn fees by linking to Amazon.com and affiliated sites.

These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on warmcozyhome.com send directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies ( such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons ) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and / or to personalize the advertising content that you see.

warmcozyhome.com has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers.You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. warmcozyhome.com’s privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites.If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers’ respective websites.

Some data controllers and data processors will have an obligation to appoint a data protection officer (DPO). The basic obligation is set out in Article 37(1) of the GDPR:

“(1) The controller and the processor shall designate a data protection officer in any case where: (a) the processing is carried out by a public authority or body, except for courts acting in their judicial capacity; (b) the core activities of the controller or the processor consist of processing operations which, by virtue of their nature, their scope and/or their purposes, require regular and systematic monitoring of data subjects on a large scale; or (c) the core activities of the controller or the processor consist of processing on a large scale of special categories of data pursuant to Article 9 and personal data relating to criminal convictions and offences referred to in Article 10.”

Article 13(1)(b) of the GDPR provides that:

“(1) Where personal data relating to a data subject are collected from the data subject, the controller shall, at the time when personal data are obtained, provide the data subject with all of the following information … (b) the contact details of the data protection officer, where applicable”.

See also Article 14(1)(b).

Insert contact details of the appointed data protection officer (if any).
